Have these items gone moldy?
怎么了 发霉了
If not, why display them in the sun?
要拿出来晒晒呀
Hey, where are you going?
来来来 你往哪儿拿
Put them here.
放这儿 放这儿
Today's a nice day,
今儿天好
making it perfect to
拿出来晒晒
display them.
晒晒
Fruits
水果
spoil fast.
放不长
I assumed you don't know that.
您还知道呢
Dad,
爸
the turtle is missing.
老甲找不着了
I'll buy you five more.
我再给你买五只去
Buy them in pairs.
买双别买单
Okay.
好嘞
Where's Yunjie?
云阶呢
She was just here.
她刚才在呢
Mom.
妈
What happened to you?
怎么变成这个样子了
Yunjie, you're back.
云阶啊 你回来了
Are you alright?
你没事吧
I'm fine.
没事 妈没事
Where's dad?
爸呢
I'm here.
这儿呢
Yunjie, you're back.
云阶 你回来了
Where have you been?
干什么去了
What's so important?
有什么活这么重要啊
Mom gets sick,
妈都病成这个样子了
you should look after her.
你也不知道照顾照顾
In usual,
你平时
you are attentive, yet now
不照顾挺起劲的吗
mom doesn't even get a glass of water.
床头连杯水都没有
I'm so disappointed in you.
关键时刻掉链子
I...
那个
He is also feeling unwell.
你爸也不舒服了
I'm actually sick too.
我也病了
You're sick too?
你也病了
No touch.
不碰
It's contagious.
传染 传染
Keep your distance.
保持距离
Then why are you standing here?
那你还瞎溜达什么呀
Go lie down.
躺床上去
I...
我
Hurry up.
快点
Come here.
快 乖
Just do as she says.
闺女让你躺你就躺
Fine, I'll
躺会儿 躺会儿
lie down.
躺会儿
Tuck in the quilt
盖好被子
like mom does.
像我妈那样
You two
你说说你俩
are adults.
多大岁数的人了
how come you can't look after yourselves?
自己身体都照顾不好
When you're not feeling well,
身体都不舒服
you should rest in bed.
还不躺床上休息
Good thing I'm back.
这还好是我回来了
I can take care of you both.
还能照顾照顾你俩
I'm off to buy rice soup and medicine.
我下去买粥买药
You two get some rest.
你俩好好休息
Don't move.
不许乱动
It's too much to worry about.
太不让人省心了
You're really sick, huh?
还真病了你
Dr. Yu.
俞医生
Ms. Chen.
陈小姐
This is for you.
这个
Rice soup again?
又熬粥了
No, it's noodles.
不 这次是面
You have low blood sugar,
你不是低血糖吗
so this is good for you.
精细碳水 吃了升糖快
Sorry for always
不好意思啊
troubling you.
总是麻烦你
Never mind.
没事
When I was little
我小时候
my grandpa would make me noodles
不舒服了
whenever I felt unwell,
外公就给我煮碗面
and I'd feel better.
吃了就好了
Okay,
好
thank you.
那谢谢了
Well,
那个
I'll leave you alone.
我不打扰你了
I'm leaving.
我先走了
Bye.
拜拜
Is it not good?
不好喝吗
It's good.
好喝啊
Yummy.
好喝
It's just not mealtime yet.
这 这不是没到饭点吗
Yeah.
对
So you don't want it now?
那你就是不想喝了呗
Of course I do.
想啊
Alright, give it to me.
行了行了 给我吧
Give it to me.
给我 给我
There's medicine over there.
那儿还有药
I bought it.
我买了
Remember to take it later.
一会儿你俩记得吃了
Your mom doesn't need it.
你妈不吃药
Why?
为什么
She already took hers,
你妈吃过了
for 12 hours.
十二个小时的
What about you?
那你呢
I'll take the medicine.
我可以啊
I can take it.
我是可以啊
Though my cold symptoms are mild,
我虽然感冒症状轻
I still need the medicine.
但是我需要吃药
Right?
对吧
Yeah.
对
Remember to take it later.
一会儿记得把药吃了
What should we do?
怎么办
We'll just lie here?
我们就这样躺着
I have to keep lying here.
我肯定是得一直躺着呀
What about me?
那我呢
You just
你要不就
lie down with me for a bit.
陪我躺会儿
Alright,
行吧
I'll lie down for a bit.
躺会儿吧
Good.
行
Our daughter bought us rice soup.
吃上闺女买的粥了
Yeah.
是啊
Yet it would be better
要是能有口咸菜
with some pickles.
就更好了
Don't move.
你别动
Stay here.
躺着
I'll go check.
我去看看
So heavy.
这么沉
So much stuff.
这么多
Yunjie,
云阶
let me do it.
我来收拾
Stop it.
你别动
Go.
出去
Get your rest.
好好休息去
Do you know
你知道东西
how to do it?
放哪儿吗
You're in the kitchen.
厨房啊
I'll find out once I put them away.
我放完我就知道了
I don't get it.
我就纳了闷了
Why did you buy so much?
你买这么多东西干吗呀
For eating.
买的吃啊
Can you finish all this?
你吃得完吗 这么多
Your mom
你妈妈
is sick, right?
她是不是病了
Doesn't she need to eat
一个病人是不是需要
more nutritious food?
补充点营养啊
Sick people should eat light.
病人得需要吃清淡点
Look at what you bought:
你看你买的什么
luncheon meat
午餐肉
and
还有什么
ham sausages.
火腿肠
I can eat them.
能吃 我能吃
No, I'm sick too.
不 我 我病了
I'm sick too.
是不是我也病了
I need nutrition as well.
我是不是也得补充营养
And there are these
那还有这个
big cherries.
大车厘子
Why didn't I have them when I was sick?
我病的时候怎么没有呢
You...
你
You can eat them whenever you like.
你不病的时候也能吃
Since you're back,
这不你回来了吗
you can eat them now.
来 现在就打开吃
Come on.
来
Stay back.
退
Go rest.
你好好歇着去吧
The kitchen is my domain.
厨房是我的阵地
I won't let you do this.
我不允许你胡来
Just do as I say.
你听话
No, you do as I say.
你才听话呢
I'm your dad.
我是你爸
But you're sick now.
你现在是个生病的爸爸
Do as I tell you,
听我的
and go rest.
回去休息去
Do you think
你是不是觉得
you've grown up?
你自己长大了
Do you think you...
你是不是觉得你
You...
你
Who's there?
谁啊
I'll talk to you later.
我一会儿再跟你说
Lanxiang,
兰香姐
why are you here?
你怎么来了
To check on you.
我来看看你们啊
This must be Yunjie.
这是云阶吧
Look how tall she's gotten.
都长这么高了
Yunjie,
云阶
this is your aunt.
叫表姑
Which aunt?
哪个表姑啊
I cared for you when you were 1-3 years old.
我把你从一岁看到三岁
Don't you remember?
你不记得了
Right,
对
your aunt Lanxiang.
兰香表姑嘛
Hi, aunt Lanxiang.
兰香表姑好
Hi, aunt...
表姑好
Please come in, Lanxiang.
快请进 兰香姐
Your house hasn't changed.
你们家都没变
Where's Meng'an?
梦安呢
My mom's sick.
我妈病了
Sick?
病了
Then I came at the right time.
那我来对了
Good.
舒坦
I'm full of joy now.
真是舒坦
Finally, I get a chance
让我逮着机会
to have Meng'an
让我姐屁颠 屁颠地
follow me around for once.
跟在我屁股后头一回
Your sister's had a hard time,
你姐也不容易啊
having a second child at her age.
这么大岁数怀二胎
She really has.
我姐确实挺不容易的
What about me?
那我容易了吗
Since I was little,
那从小到大
I've been eating what she left,
我吃我姐吃剩下的
using what she didn't need,
用我姐用剩下的
and wearing her hand-me-downs.
穿我姐穿剩下的
This time,
这次
I'm going to
我要把这些
taking revenge.
统统都还回去
I always thought you didn't care about it,
我一直以为你心挺大的
I didn't expect you
没想到你还
to be jealous of your own sister.
吃你姐的醋啊
It's not jealousy.
这不叫吃醋
It's revenge.
这叫报复
I've endured too many
我小时候
grievances growing up.
受的委屈可太多了
Your dad and I
我和你爸
never mistreated you.
从小可没亏着你啊
All the grievances I've endured
那我受的委屈
came from my sister
都是你和爸
when you and Dad
不在我和我姐
weren't there for me.
跟前的时候受的
Looking back,
现在想一想
those weren't just grievances.
那都不叫委屈
They were
那应该叫
exploitation,
压榨
harassment,
欺负
and even bullying.
甚至是霸凌
Otherwise, how would you behave?
要不怎么管得住你呀
True.
也是啊
I've decided.
我想好了
Look,
你看啊
Yunjie is doing a great job
这个云阶管熊熊
with Xiongxiong.
管得挺好的
In the future,
将来
I'll teach
我要教教我
my second child
肚子里的老二
to take good care of
让他好好管一管
my sister's second child.
我姐肚子里的老二
Wait.
你等等
Your second child taking care
老二肚子里的老二
of the second child of Meng'an?
要管老大肚子里的老二
That's the strangest prenatal
这是我听到过
education I've ever heard.
最奇葩的胎教
Yunjie,
云阶啊
I took care of you from age one to three.
我把你从一岁带到三岁
You really don't remember me?
你真不记得我了
I was only three at the time.
我当时才三岁
How could I remember?
怎么可能记得
Right.
也是啊
Your house hasn't changed
你说你们家这么多年
a bit over the years.
还真是一点都没变啊
Aunt,
表姑
we're about to move.
我们马上就要搬家了
To a big apartment with a river view.
江景大平层
It's so good.
可好了
Really?
真的
That's great.
那太好了
Stop doing that.
你别干了
Come here
来
and hand me the stuff.
你到这边来给我递东西
I'll organize it.
我来码
Okay.
好
Hey,
来
give that to me.
这个给我
Who's here?
谁来了
I heard Yunjie calling aunt.
我听孩子喊表姑
Lanxiang,
兰香
Lanxiang is here.
兰香姐来了
Lanxiang?
兰香姐
Didn't we already tell her
不是已经跟她说
not to come?
不用来了吗
Why is she here again?
怎么又来了
Didn't you call your sister?
你没给你姐打电话吗
I did tell her.
我跟她说了呀
Then how come?
那 这怎么回事啊
I'll call her again.
我再打一个
Hello?
喂
Hello, Jing.
喂 姐
Lanxiang went to your place?
兰香去你家了
Yes.
对呀
Jing,
姐
didn't my brother-in-law tell you
姐夫不是跟你说过了吗
not to introduce Lanxiang
不让你介绍兰香姐
here?
到这儿来
He said no,
你姐夫说不让
but you didn't say no.
你也没说不要啊
Right?
是不是
Meng'an said
梦安不是答应说
she would help.
给问问吗
Let me tell you again.
我再跟你说一遍
Mengxin doesn't need
梦心家里她不需要
anyone at home.
她不缺人哪
Well,
那个
how about this?
大姐 要不然这样
Let Lanxiang stay here first.
让兰香表姐先住家里头
She can look for work slowly.
工作的事再慢慢找
See?
你看
See? Meng'an knows how to get things done.
这还是梦安会办事
Listen,
我跟你说呀
Lanxiang has had a hard time.
这个兰香特别不容易
We
咱们呢
should help if we can.
能帮就帮一下呗
I'll hang up now.
先挂了啊
Are you sure to keep her here?
真的先留下
At least for today.
今天肯定走不了了吧
I'll go get ready.
那我去准备一下
Welcome, Lanxiang.
兰香姐来了
Meng'an.
弟妹
Long time no see.
好久不见了
You haven't aged
你说这么多年
a bit over the years.
一点都不上年纪
I'm old.
老了
Yunjie is turning 16,
云阶都得十六了吧
and you must be over 40 by now.
那你得四十多了
Back home,
要在我们那儿
women your age could be grandmothers
这你这个年纪过两年
in just a few more years.
都能做姥姥了
Yet look at you,
你看你
still looking so young and beautiful.
还这么年轻漂亮
What? I'm only 14.
什么呀 我才十四
How could mom be close to being a grandmother?
我妈怎么就快做姥姥了
Nominal age.
虚岁
She means in terms of nominal age.
你表姑说的是虚岁
Yes.
对
I don't like nominal age.
我不要虚岁
Come on,
来来来
have a seat.
坐坐坐
take a seat.
来
How have you been recently?
你怎么样啊最近
What's your plan for coming to Chunjiang?
来春江是 有什么打算
My son is still in school.
这不你大侄还在上学吗
I'm thinking of finding a job
我想还是到城里来
in the city.
找份工作
I want to check if Mengxin
想看看你妹妹那儿
is in need of staff.
还缺人不
Xin already
心心那儿
has a driver and nanny.
司机和保姆都安排好了
It's not good for us to intervene.
我们提换人也不合适
I thought we can wait
我是想再等等
and try to find another
我再帮你联系联系
job for you.
看看别的家
Just stay here
你就踏踏实实
for now.
在家里头住着
Aside from
你看我们家
having a few more items,
除了东西多了点哈
our house is unchanged from before.
基本上都没变样 是吧
Work will
工作嘛
come slowly.
慢慢遇
Let's find a good one.
咱找个好人家
Okay.
好 好
Meng'an,
弟妹
you're right.
我听你的
Thank you.
谢谢你了啊
It's nothing.
没事
Haven't eaten yet?
还没吃饭吧
I'll make dinner.
对 我去做饭
Hurry up.
快去
No.
不不不
Lin, stop.
临临 你不动
I'll do it.
你们都不动 我来
No need.
不用
I'm familiar with your kitchen.
你们家厨房我熟
I cook more quickly.
我快
You can just
你们都不动
wait to be served.
等着吃就行了啊
Dad,
老爸
you're losing your job again.
这是又要光荣下岗了呀
What do you mean again?
什么又又又的
Yunjie,
云阶啊
come here.
来
I need to tell you something.
妈跟你说点事
What is it?
什么事啊
Let's talk on the bed.
上床
Come.
来
Sit down.
坐会儿
What's up?
什么事啊
Well,
是这样啊
your aunt Lanxiang
你兰香表姑呢
might be staying with us
可能会在家里边
for a while.
住一段时间
Even though she's
虽然她是咱们的
a distant relative,
远房亲戚
there are some things
但是家里有一些事
we shouldn't let her know.
还是不宜让她知道
Why?
为什么
I'm worried
我是担心
if she knows,
如果她知道了
your aunt might know.
你大姑可能就知道了
And if your aunt knows,
你大姑要知道了
the whole world will know.
全世界就都知道了
It's okay if the whole world knows,
全世界知道也没关系
but she'll criticize us,
但她会批评我们
lecture us,
教育我们
and regulate us.
支配我们
Then what
那什么事情
shouldn't she know?
不能让她知道呀
Your dad's unemployment
你爸之前失业的事
must not be mentioned.
绝对不能让她知道
Okay.
好
And your mom's
还有你妈的事
situation too.
也不能让她知道
What about you?
你啥事啊
It's just your mom
就 就是你妈
loves work.
热爱工作
She's ill,
又生病了
but still working.
还带病工作
We can't let her know.
不能让她知道
Also, don't let her know
我没考好的事情
about my poor exam results.
也不能让她知道
Definitely.
不说
Anything else
还有别的事情
she shouldn't know?
不能让她知道吗
Let's think about it.
再好好想想
Yes, let's think.
对 我们再想想
Okay.
想想
See?
看见了吗
That's the difference
这就是
between a pro and an amateur.
专业和业余的差别
Looks like dad still has a lot of room
看来老爸还有很大的
for improvement.
进步空间呀
Plenty of room.
那空间大了去了
Your dad's
你看你爸
like a mole,
跟个地老鼠似的
totally out of place.
根本插不上手
Just go take a rest.
你出去吧
It's okay.
没事 没事
But you can't just abandon him.
那你也不能始乱终弃呀
You know
你要知道
aunt Lanxiang can't
表姑不可能
stay with us forever.
在咱家一辈子呀
Still have to depend on your dad in the future.
以后还得靠你爸 是吧
This smells just like the Chunjiang
这跟我吃的春江鱼宴
fish banquet I had.
一个味啊
Didn't fill up on the rice soup?
刚刚粥没吃饱是吧
But it's mealtime now.
这不是到饭点了吗
Hurry up.
快快快 赶快
Is it good?
吃好了
Great.
太好了
I'll clean up now.
那我收了啊
Stay still,
谁都不要动
I've got this.
都放下
Leave it to me.
都不动手啊
I can handle it.
听我的
Lanxiang,
兰香姐
I can't cook better than you,
做饭我是做不过你
but I can handle
但是收拾碗筷
washing dishes.
我还是能干的
As long as I'm here,
以后只要有我在
you won't have to do anything.
什么活都不用你们干
Teach me later.
回头教教我啊
Sure, no problem.
行 没问题
Thanks, aunt.
谢谢表姑
Trust me.
不用你干
I should
我还
take it to her.
还是给她拿过去吧
Better not go over there.
算了 你还是别去了
Lanxiang came unexpectedly
兰香姐来得突然
and feels a bit awkward.
她自己也挺不好意思的
She's working hard
这么努力干活
to make
也是想给自己
a good impression.
找个台阶下
You should understand it.
那你就给她呗
Agree.
就是
It's time for you to take a break.
刚好你也休息休息
After she finds a job,
等她找到工作之后
check
你去问问
the market rate
市场价格是多少
and we'll pay her.
咱给她包个红包
It'll be worth
不白干
her effort.
不就行了吗
Yes.
要给
So, Wanzhen,
所以婉真
are you now
你现在
working in real estate sales?
就是在做楼市销售呗
Part-time or full-time?
兼职 还是专职
Full-time.
专职的
But I just started.
不过我刚开始做
Grace,
格蕾丝
if you want to buy a property,
你要是有置业的打算
feel free to contact me.
你可以联系我啊
Actually,
我跟你说
recently,
我最近呢
I'm thinking of moving.
还真的有换房的打算
Really?
是吗
Pregnant?
怀孕了
Congratulations.
好啊
Look.
你看看
Check the layout.
你看看这个户型
It's 140 square meters in size.
一百四十平的
Perfect for you.
特别合适你
Really?
是吗
It has reserved space
将来第二胎的空间
for a future second child.
都预留出来了
Don't say that.
可算了吧
A second child?
二胎
I'm still struggling with
我现在这是头胎
the first one.
头得我头都大
When's your due date?
那预产期什么时候啊
In three months.
还有三个月
Soon.
快了呀
Pregnancy is tough.
怀孕真的辛苦
It turns out you are right.
所以还是你是对的
You know?
你知道吗
Look,
我觉得 你看啊
we're the same age,
咱俩呢 是同龄
and here I am, an elderly pregnancy woman,
我现在就是个高龄产妇
while you've had two children,
你孩子都生完了
who are already up now,
都可以跑了
freeing you from worry,
你也不用操心
allowing you to work with ease.
你就可以安心地工作嘛
But I believe your choice is better.
我还是觉得你这样好
You're a director now,
你现在都是总监了
meaning a stable career,
那事业稳定了
and more security
然后再生孩子
for both the child and yourself
那对自己
once the baby is born.
对孩子都负责任
And the pain of giving birth
而且生育的苦
is nothing compared to
比起养育的难
the challenges of raising a child.
不算什么
To tell you the truth,
你是不知道
I'm struggling now.
我现在是不行了
I don't know
我也不知道
what's wrong.
是怎么回事啊
Perhaps it's because I'm getting older.
年纪大了
I feel like I lack energy, always feeling sleepy,
觉得精力不够
and I can't pull all-nighters anymore.
还老犯困 还熬不了夜
You're familiar
那咱们的工作
with our work.
你是知道的嘛
Engaging in one project
来一个项目
means staying in a hotel
一住酒店
for months.
就要住好几个月
At the company,
我现在呢
I'm pretty much
在我们公司就算是个
on the fringe,
边缘人
no longer a main player,
根本做不了主力
relegated to a support position.
就让我打辅助
So my husband
所以我老公
often says to me at home,
经常在家里跟我说
"For the little money and the work amount
钱少事多
You might as well quit
你不如不做
and stay home raising our kid."
回家带孩子得了
I'm nearly persuaded.
说得我都有点犹豫
You must stick with it.
你一定要坚持啊
I hate to admit it,
不怕你笑话
but I'm a bad example.
我就是反面的典型
You?
你
Isn't your husband doing well?
你老公不是做挺好的吗
That's my ex-husband.
那是前夫了
I'm raising my kids by myself now.
我现在一个人带孩子
So, you're in sales now.
所以你现在在做销售
How did that happen?
怎么会这样呢
So I believe in
所以呢 我觉得呀
taking
这个命运
control of my own fate.
还是要把握在自己手里
But it's
不过还好
not too late now.
现在也不晚呢
Alright.
行
I'll definitely
这个房子呢
buy this house from you.
我必须在你这儿买
Thanks, Grace.
谢谢格蕾丝
I'll have another look at the manual.
再看看啊
Okay.
好
Aren't you thinking of
你就没打算
going back to your old field?
再重新回到老本行
I have thought about it,
不是没有想过啊
but I've been
但是我离开
away for so long.
这个行业好久了
My experience and age
我的资历啊 年龄啊
are disadvantages.
都没有什么优势
I understand.
明白
Mr. Zhou is here. Hi, Mr. Zhou.
周总来了 周总
Hi, Grace.
格蕾丝
Windy.
温蒂啊
Zhou Yao.
周耀
Old colleagues' reunion.
老同事大聚会喽
Indeed.
还真是
You're working now?
你出来工作了
Are you working here?
在这儿上班吗
No.
没有
I'm now
我现在是
in real estate sales.
地产公司的销售
Here's our company's brochure.
这是我们公司的楼书
If you're interested,
你要是感兴趣的话
take a look.
可以看一看
Here's my calling card.
这是我的名片
Call me
你要是有什么需要
if you need anything.
可以给我打电话
I'll read it for sure.
我一定看
I have a meeting,
我约了人开会
so I got to go now.
我先走了
Okay, go ahead.
好好好 你忙
Keep in touch.
回头联系
Okay, bye.
好 再见
Bye.
再见
Alright, I'm leaving.
那行 那我先走了
Take care.
走吧 注意安全
Okay, bye.
好 拜拜
Bye.
拜拜
Excuse me.
来
Enjoy some fruit.
吃点水果啊
This is Lanxiang.
这 兰香姐
Wanzhen,
婉真
have you met before?
你们见过吧
Yes,
见过
when Yunjie was little.
那云阶的小时候
Yes.
对
We've met before.
不见过嘛
Yeah.
对对对
I think she looks
我觉得她状态
much better now.
比以前好多了
Prettier, isn't she?
人也漂亮了 是吧
Right?
是吧
Let me tell you,
我跟你讲
she's really impressive now.
她现在可厉害了
Keep it up.
保持住啊 保持住
I'm going to do groceries.
我去买点菜去
Okay.
好
Have fun.
你坐着
Why are you
怎么今天有空
here today?
上我们家来啊
Slacking off during work hours,
上班时间摸鱼
that's not like you.
这可不太像你啊
Staying home during work hours
那上班时间在家待着
isn't like you either.
也不像你啊
Wanna know why?
想知道原因吗
Yes.
想啊
Miscarriage prevention.
安胎
You've made up your mind?
想通了
Yes, I've decided to keep the baby.
想通了 也决定要了
I used to
之前
find a lot of reasons
老是跟自己说了
not to have the baby,
很多不想要的理由
but
但是其实
deep inside,
我自己知道
I still have feelings
我对这个孩子
for the baby.
还是有感情的
But my heart
但是那个心呢
felt unsettled.
就老是揪着
Once I decided to keep it,
可是一决定要了之后啊
I felt so much more at ease.
我整个人都觉得踏实了
You get it, right?
我跟你说你肯定懂吧
Just like when you decided
就跟你要离婚那时候
to divorce.
是一样的
What did the doctor say?
那医生怎么说呀
Just take care of myself.
好好养着呗
As an elderly pregnant woman,
反正就高龄产妇
I should avoid stress and anger,
不要动怒 不要生气
and eat more progesterone.
然后多吃点孕酮什么的
I think it will be fine.
我觉得没什么大问题
I even want to go back to work.
我都想回去上班了
All the reasons given for not having baby
那以前不生的理由呢
no longer hold water.
都不是理由
Now I eat my words.
我打脸了
It tells us that
这说明什么呀
in the face of genuine desire,
在真正内心的渴望面前
all external obstacles
一切外在的阻碍
are but paper tigers.
都是纸老虎
You're right.
你对
Alright, let's talk about you.
行了 说说你吧
Did you need something
找我是有什么事啊
or just want to chat?
还是想单纯地跟我聊聊
Just to chat with you.
想跟你聊聊
Okay.
好呀
I was promoting properties
我今天找我老同事
to old colleagues today,
推销房
back at where
回到了我从前
I used to work.
上班的地方
The financial building
江边那栋
by the river?
金融大楼
Feeling nostalgic?
感慨了
Seeing old colleagues
看着以前的老同事
as directors
现在不是总监
or bosses,
就是老板
and watching them start new projects
我看着他们做新的项目
and have meetings,
开项目会
I felt a lot of envy.
我特别地羡慕
I really miss
好怀念
those days in investment banking.
从前做投行的日子
Instead of missing the past,
与其怀念过去的日子
miss the person you used to be.
不如怀念过去的自己
Yes,
是
I used to be
想想以前的我啊
so confident,
那意气风发
believing I was the best
我都觉得我是全世界
investor in the world.
最优秀的投资人
Fresh out of college,
我大学毕业那会儿
I even fancied myself
还觉得自己会
becoming the best journalist
成为全中国
in all of China.
最厉害的新闻记者呢
Everyone has dreams after all.
谁还没点梦想啊
Do you think I still
那你说我
have a chance to return to
还有没有机会回到
the investment industry?
投资行业啊
Would you like to return?
想吗
Yes.
想
Then go for it.
那就去
But the finance industry
可是现在的金融行业
is so competitive now.
竞争太激烈了
Even top graduates
连刚毕业的高材生
struggle to find jobs.
找工作都难
Me,
你说我
after being away for so many years,
离开这个行业这么多年
even if an opportunity comes,
就算机会落在我头上
I might not catch it.
我恐怕都抓不住
I don't agree.
这个我不同意啊
If the opportunity
如果机会真的
does come,
落在你头上
you have to do your utmost
抓不住也得抓
to grab it.
赖也得赖上去
You studied
你本来就是
in this major
学这个专业的呀
with a master's degree,
还是个硕士
plus five or six years of experience.
又有五六年的工作经验
You're
这业务上
qualified.
没问题啊
It's true,
是没问题
but others are qualified too.
可是人家也没问题呀
And they're younger.
那人家还年轻呢
True.
也是
Your industry
你们这个行业吧
has a high entry barrier.
就是门槛太高
Those who can enter
但凡能进去的
have similar
估计硬件水平
skill levels.
都差不多吧
So, compete on your soft skills:
那咱就跟他拼软件啊
execution,
执行能力
management,
管理能力
stress handling,
抗压能力
and coordination.
协调能力
You're already divorced.
咱婚都离了
Don't you already have those skills?
这些能力还没有吗
Don't doubt me.
你不用质疑我啊
Really.
真的
If you think
你要觉得
I'm like a female warrior,
我是个女武松的话
then let me ask you,
那我请问
are female warriors' friends
女武松的小姐妹
weaklings?
是吃素的吗
Of course not.
对呀
Meng'an,
梦安
you're really my energy booster.
你真的是我的充电宝宝
Here are my antennas.
给我两根天线
Chatting with you
在我郁闷的时候
when I'm down
一找你聊天
makes me enlightened.
我真的是豁然开朗
How do you cultivate?
你怎么修炼的
Cultivate?
修炼吗
By self-acceptance.
自洽呀
Do you know the biggest difference
你知道我们跟年轻人
between us and younger generation?
最大的差别是什么吗
Young people
年轻人呢
accept themselves reluctantly,
是委屈着自洽
while we accept with pleasure.
我们呢 是愉快地自洽
Though life is harsh,
虽然岁月是把杀猪刀
we still possess the ability
但我们依然有能力
to face the gifts
坦然面对
it bestows upon us
岁月给我们的
with grace.
馈赠
Quite a journalist,
不愧是学新闻的
you're great with words.
张口就来啊
I'm good at stirring emotions.
煽情能力还是有的
Meng'an.
梦安
Go for it.
去
I got your back.
我支持你
It took you for so long.
去这么长时间啊
Mr. Jia,
贾总
I browsed through the mall.
我跑了整个商场
These two cosmetics
这两个化妆品
are indisputably
绝对是整个商场里
the most luxurious
最高端 最高端
in the entire mall.
最高端的化妆品了
Are these the most expensive?
是最贵的呀
Definitely.
那必须的
You can count on me.
我办事您放心啊
Would you like something to eat?
你吃不吃啊
No, thanks.
我不吃了
I ran too fast.
我跑太急了
Is someone missing me?
谁想我了
Mrs. Jia, hello.
贾太 你好
What are you doing here?
你怎么到我家门口了
Are you interested in your
有没有兴趣了解一下
husband's whereabouts?
您先生的行踪啊
No.
没兴趣
Look at this.
您看这个
These are candid shots
都是我们一些
from our external
外线的摄影师
photographers.
无意间拍到的
It's free.
免费的
Take a look.
您先看一看
What's this?
这什么呀
It's just my husband shopping.
不就是我老公买买买吗
Toys, bags, and cosmetics.
玩具 包 化妆品
Why are you taking pictures of these?
你拍这些干吗
Look at this.
您看这个
Two sets of luxury cosmetics.
贵妇化妆品套装 两套
What wrong about two sets?
两套怎么了
One for my face and one for my feet.
我一套擦脸 一套擦脚
Bye, Mrs. Jia.
贾太慢走
I'm willing to help
随时随地
anytime, anywhere.
为您排忧解难
Your dad only bought you this?
你爸就给你买的这个
Yeah.
对啊
What about building blocks?
大积木呢
He didn't buy me building blocks.
我爸没给我买大积木呀
Mom, look.
妈 你看
I don't have this yellow one,
这个黄的我没有
or this red one.
这红的也是
And this blue one neither.
这蓝的也没
It's so cool.
好酷啊
Safe travels.
一路平安
Okay.
好好好
Thanks so much.
太感谢了
You did me a favor today.
今天真的给我面子
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
Let's meet again and talk.
咱俩再见面好好聊
Okay?
好吧
Okay.
好好好 好
Take care.
好 您慢点啊
Bye.
拜拜啊
Okay.
好
Honey.
老婆
Take a look
看 老婆
at what I've bought for you.
我给你买什么了
Luxury face cream.
贵妇面霜
Use this one in the morning,
早上用这个
and this one at night.
晚上用这个
Shouldn't there be two sets?
不应该有两套吗
Honey,
老婆
if you like it,
你要喜欢
I'll buy another set tomorrow,
明儿我再买一套
one set for your face
咱一套专门擦脸用
and the other for your feet,
另外一套咱擦脚用
as long as you like it.
乖 只要你喜欢
What else?
别的呢
I'm such a fool, honey.
我太笨了 我的大媳妇
My fault, honey.
我错了 老婆
Let's go shopping
明儿咱们一家三口
tomorrow.
逛街去
We'll shop from street to street,
咱从街头逛到街尾
buying from the first store
从第一家店
to the last,
买到最后一家店
as long as you like it.
只要你喜欢
Honey,
老婆
I was wrong.
我错了 我错了
I'm guilty.
我有罪
I'm sorry.
我错了
Mom,
妈
come have breakfast.
快来吃早饭了
Our breakfast is upgraded today,
咱们家今天早餐升级了
moved from the usual trio.
不再吃那老三样了
What's wrong with the usual trio?
老三样怎么了
You
老三样平时
used to enjoy them.
你不是也吃得很开心吗
But now we have something better.
现在不是有更好的吗
I need to praise my aunt more
我得多夸夸姑姑
to make you ambitious.
让你好有上进心
Trying to provoke me, eh?
刺激我
Don't disparage others.
捧高踩低 不鼓励啊
I learned it from you.
我这不跟你学的吗
When did I do that?
我什么时候这样了
I'm done eating.
我吃好了
I'll bring He Lu a rice cake.
我给何璐再带个米粿
She'll definitely love it.
她肯定爱吃
Do you feel a bit
是不老觉得
awkward about
蹭她们家的车上学
riding their car to school?
有点不好意思
I'm riding their car today.
这话说得 今天还蹭
Be careful on the way.
路上小心点啊
Bye.
拜拜
Yunjie, take it slow.
云阶 慢点啊
Here, Meng'an,
来 弟妹
this is for you.
这是你的
It's hot.
热的啊
Thanks.
谢谢 谢谢
Leave them here.
不收 不收
Take a seat.
坐着
Let's chat.
说会儿话
You made such a great breakfast.
这早餐做得这么丰盛
Must got up really early.
特早就起来了吧
I usually wake up early.
我觉少 起得早
Let's grab a bite.
快吃
Have more.
多吃点
Meng'an,
弟妹
what
我想问问你
exactly is wrong with you?
你到底得了什么病啊
When I worked
我原来在
at the home service company,
家政公司的时候
I studied nutrition.
我学过那个营养搭配
I'd like to help you
我想好好给你
improve your health.
调理调理身体
No need.
不用
I was just feeling unwell
我就是前两天
a few days ago,
身体不太舒服
but I'm fine now.
都好了
I was planning
我还想着说
to go back to work tomorrow.
明天就上班了呢
Tomorrow?
你明天
Aren't you on a vacation?
你不是还有假期吗
I'm fine to go back to work.
都好了 就去上班呗
Can I have a cup of coffee?
我能不能喝杯咖啡啊
No.
不行
You can't drink coffee.
不能喝咖啡
Why drink coffee?
你喝什么咖啡呀
I made this soybean milk myself.
这个豆浆是我自己磨的
I boiled it. It's so good,
都开了好几回 可香了
unlike the watered-down ones
不像外面那些豆浆
you get outside.
掺着那么多水
Give it a try.
你尝尝
Okay.
对
Soybean milk
喝豆浆好
is healthy.
健康
Yes.
对对对
I'll drink it.
喝豆浆
Is it good?
香吧
Yes.
香
Have more.
多吃点啊
Well...
这
Meng'an,
弟妹
are you pregnant?
你不会是怀上了吧
My bad, I didn't notice it.
怪我了 我没看出来
Why didn't you tell me?
这你们怎么也不说呢
Well,
不
we didn't mention it
之前不是
because
不太稳定
it wasn't stable.
就都没说
Yes.
对
Does Jing know?
那静姐知道吗
She doesn't know.
她不知道
We haven't even told An's parents.
连她父母 我们都没说
Got it.
那我明白了
I won't tell her.
先不说
Don't.
千万别说
We don't want false hope.
免得空欢喜
Okay.
好好好
You cant eat greasy food now.
那你现在不能吃油腻的
I'll make you an egg.
我去给你卧个蛋
Oh no.
完了
The whole world will be informed.
全世界要知道了
Get ready.
准备准备吧
Alright.
好吧
Flowers burst into bloom in the spring
春天里那个百花香
Warm sun shines overhead
朗里格朗里格朗里格
Honey.
老婆
What?
干吗
I'm going out.
我出去一趟啊
You're in a good mood.
你心情不错呀
Where are you going?
去干吗啊
Honey, I'm meeting someone.
老婆 我去见个人
Meeting who?
见谁啊
Dressed so formally.
穿得那么一本正经
An important client.
见个重要客户
Important?
重要
Who's important?
谁重要
You're important, honey.
你重要 老婆
To me, you're the most
我心里头
important person.
你最重要
My heart is all yours,
我的心里只有你
no one else.
绝对没有她
I'll be back soon.
我一定快去快回
Honey.
老婆
Mr. Jia,
贾总
are these the two gifts?
是带这两样礼品吗
Alright, good.
行行行 好
Hurry up and go.
快走 快走 快走
Lanxiang,
兰香姐
come here.
你来一下
Okay.
好
Come.
来
Take a sit.
坐
What's up?
啥事
Listen,
我跟你说啊
this is a tablet,
这是一个平板电脑
and this is a phone.
这是一个手机
You can
你呢
send them to Ming and Pingping.
回头寄给大明和萍萍
The kids are grown up now,
孩子都大了
they can definitely use them.
肯定能用得上
I... can't,
我我 不
these are too valuable.
这个太贵重了
I can't accept them.
这我可不能要 弟妹
It's okay.
不贵重
They're not new,
不是新的
just things we've used before.
是我们以前用过的
You
你呢
just send them to the kids.
回头就给俩孩子都寄走
Great.
太好了
The kids need
这 孩子上学
them for school.
老用得着这个
I could never bring myself to buy them.
我一直没舍得给他买
Thank you so much.
太感谢了啊
Now you don't have to buy.
不用买了 有了
Also,
来
here's 2,000 yuan.
这里呢 还有两千块钱
Take it.
你拿着
I really can't take this, Meng'an.
这个我真不能要 弟妹
You've already
你说我在这儿
provided me food and a room.
又吃又住的
It's good enough for you
你不跟我要钱
not to ask me for money.
就已经很好了
I can't take it.
钱我坚决不能要
If you don't want the money,
你要不想要这个钱呢
use it to buy groceries.
就拿这个钱去买菜
We'll eat
反正你买什么
whatever you buy.
我们一家三口就吃什么
You used to do that, right?
以前你不也这样吗
Fine.
行
I can do that.
这可是我的拿手活
I'll take it then.
那我就不客气了啊
I don't know how long
也不知道你在这儿
you'll be here.
能干几天
Home service companies are
现在这家政公司啊
short-staffed now.
都可缺人了
You'll probably
估计要不了两天
have to leave soon.
你就得走了
Meng'an,
弟妹
is Mengxin truly
你妹妹那边
not recruiting?
真不缺人啊
No,
不缺
she's already arranged everything.
她都安排好了
You know
你也知道的
how hard it is
心心那个人
to take care of Xin.
也是很难伺候的
I actually
其实
want to work
我还是想给
for my own family.
自己家里人干
Money isn't everything.
钱不钱的都无所谓
Really.
真的
Just offering me food is fine.
给个吃喝就行了
How can that be?
那怎么行呢
Everyone works
谁出来打工
for money.
不是为了挣点钱呀
Don't worry.
你放心
Tomorrow
明天呢
I'll go with you to the company
我就陪你去趟家政公司
and register.
咱们去登个记
If there's a suitable family,
回头有合适的人家
I'll go with you
我也陪你去看看
to check it out.
把把关
We'll find a good one.
咱们找个好的
You...
你是
You don't want to go?
你是不想去吗
Or...
还是
Meng'an, to be honest,
弟妹 我跟你说实话吧
this time
我这次
I ran away from home.
是从家里跑出来的
Why?
为什么呀
My husband
你那个表姐夫
hits me and the kids
喝点酒就打人
whenever he's drunk,
也不分个大人孩子
The kids have
这不俩孩子
gone to school now,
都出去上学了吗
and I couldn't
我在家里
stay at home anymore.
也实在是待不住了
I thought I'd find a job.
我就寻思出来找点活干
But wherever I went,
可是我去一家
he followed.
他就跟着去了
Before I finished work,
活还没干完呢
he'd throw a fit for money.
他就撒泼要钱
People are scared of him.
人家都怕了他了
So
所以
now no home service company
现在外面的家政公司
wants to hire me.
没有人会要我的
Then you stop looking for jobs,
那咱就不去
just stay here.
你就住在家里头
We're relatives,
咱们是亲戚
he probably won't dare to come here.
估计表姐夫 也不敢来
If he does,
他要真敢来闹
I'll call the police.
我就报警
Okay?
好不
Meng'an,
弟妹
thank you.
谢谢你
Thanks.
谢谢
You're welcome.
不用谢
We're family,
咱一家人
there's no need to say that.
不说两家话
I bought a soft-shelled turtle.
我买了一只甲鱼
I brought a lot of cubilose.
我带了好多燕窝
And then?
然后呢
And then...
然后
Then we came here.
没有然后 到这儿来了
Alright then,
是
I'm pregnant
怀了
with the second child.
二胎
We knew it!
我们都知道了
Come on.
来来来
Give me five.
击一下 击一下
Why are you so happy about it?
至于嘛 这高兴成这样
Who spread the news?
这这 谁传的呀
Look at you.
都是一个个儿的
What are you guys,
你们干什么工作的
spies?
情报吗
We have our sources.
我们有秘密渠道
We knew about it long ago.
这事我们早就知道了
We wanted to call you,
想给你打电话
but your mom didn't dare.
你妈又不敢
I said we'd wait for
我说等会儿再打吧
a few more days.
过几天
Actually, your mom and I knew
其实我跟你妈知道
why you didn't
你为什么
tell us.
不告诉我们俩呀
You didn't want us to worry.
你是怕我们俩担心你
What's there to worry about
这添人进口的好事
with the good news?
你担心什么呀
Exactly.
就是
Let me tell you,
我跟你说啊
your mom and I
这几天我跟你妈
are overjoyed
这喜悦的心情
these days.
溢于言表
You know?
你知道吧
For example,
你 你看
you know,
你都知道吧
before, your mom couldn't sleep
以前你妈睡觉的时候
with even the slightest bit of light,
是不有一点光就睡不着
but now
你知道现在她
she needs
怎么睡觉吗
the curtains open.
必须把窗帘打开
Why?
为什么要打开
Because she spends her nights
每天哪
gazing at the stars.
就是仰望星空啊
She's restless in bed,
在床上是辗转反侧
unable to sleep,
夜不能寐
then she paces
来回踱步
back and forth,
如坐针毡
and moves around.
就是来回溜达
Just look at my dark circles.
你看看我这大眼眶子
Yeah.
对对对
Severe.
我都什么色了
My bad.
我对不起你们了
No.
没有 没有
We're so happy,
我们高兴
full of joy.
高兴
Alright,
行了
enough with the happiness.
高兴差不多了
Let's get to the point.
说事吧
- Nothing. - The thing is...
没事 有事
What's up?
啥事啊
Got anything?
有事
Step aside.
回避
Okay.
行了
I'll check it out.
我去看看
Well,
那个
Lanxiang probably can't cook the turtle.
兰香她也不会做甲鱼吧
I need to check.
我得看看
Asking my dad to step aside,
叫我爸回避
suggests this matter is quite serious.
这事不小啊
It's not a big deal.
没什么大事
You're having a second child.
你都二胎了
Have you read
这国家政策
the national policy on this?
你读了没有
Have you learned it?
了不了解
What policy?
什么政策呀
I inquired at the police station,
我到那个派出所问过了
and it turns out these days
说那个
a child can take
现在孩子入户口啊
either
可以
the father's or mother's surname.
跟父姓也可以跟母姓
This option is also available for the first child.
头胎也可以啊
It hasn't changed for years.
多少年都没变过呀
Well,
那个
it's not like that.
不是 不是 不是
Now you can choose
现在就是说可以
the surname of the paternal
随爷爷 奶奶姓
or maternal grandparents.
也可以随姥姥 姥爷姓
Wu Lining,
吴丽宁同志
do you want the child
你是想让
to take your surname?
孩子随你的姓吗
Yes.
对
Isn't that too much?
过分了吧
No.
不不不
Not me.
说错了
It's
是
having your dad's surname, Xu,
随你爸姓 姓许
Xu?
姓许
That's also way too much.
姓许也过分呢
Too much?
过分吗
Isn't it too much?
不过分吗
Wu's daughter,
那谁老吴家他女儿
she...
她就是
What does Wu's family
老吴家跟咱家
have to do with us?
有啥关系呀
An, please...
安安
Stop it,
你别跟我撒娇
I'm not my dad.
我又不是你老伴
Seriously.
好好说
Well,
那那个
I just wish for the Xu's
我就是想
household registration
让老许家那户口本上
to carry on.
还可以延续下去
Xin and I
我跟心心
are not on the registration booklet?
不在户口本上啊
But the registration would end after you.
那不是后头没有了吗
Whose fault is that?
那怪谁呀
It's not my fault.
那也不能怪地呀
It's your dad.
那得怪种子
Fine,
怪种子
then ask my dad to talk to me.
你叫种子跟我聊啊
Dad,
爸
come on in, let's talk.
来 我跟你聊会儿
No, no.
不是 不是
This...
这就
None of your business.
没你事
It's fine.
没事 没事
Step aside.
你去干你的啊
Quite confident.
挺自信呢
Taking it all on?
大包大揽了
No...
没有 没
I know what you're thinking.
我知道你是怎么想的
You feel like
就觉得这辈子
you've let my dad down
没给我爸生个儿子
by not giving him a son, right?
挺对不起他的 是吗
How does that
你对不起他
concern us?
跟我们有啥关系呀
I'll be serious with you now.
我严肃地跟你谈一次啊
This matter
这件事情
ends here.
到此为止
Don't mention it to anyone,
跟任何人都不要再提
especially Li Lin and Yunjie.
包括李临和云阶
If you bring it up again,
你要再提的话
I'll really get angry. Got it?
我真翻脸 知道吗
Can't we discuss it?
商量商量还不行吗
No way.
没得商量
Sit properly.
你坐好
What's wrong with you?
都什么事啊这是
You mustn't give my dad a hard time later.
回家不能刁难我爸啊
Did you see
你看她刚才
her attitude just now?
说话那个态度
She was so harsh,
话说那么死
leaving no room for negotiation.
一点余地都不留
What's wrong with the surname Xu?
姓许怎么了
She bears the surname Xu as well.
她不姓许啊
Isn't that a good thing?
不挺好的事吗
She should be supporting us.
她应该帮咱们说话呀
Why is she...
她怎么
She's been like this,
从小就这样
always against me.
老怼我
Did I raise a daughter
你说我是养了个女儿
or a mother?
还是养了个妈呀
Gosh.
真是
Am I right?
你说是不是啊
You're right.
你说得太对了
She's your child. Why get angry?
自己生的 生啥气啊
It's not about anger.
不是生气
This is for
你说 这事是为了
the Xu family's good.
咱们许家好嘛
Isn't it?
这不是
Why is she so stubborn?
她怎么 那么坚决
You see...
你看
You didn't see
你没看着
her attitude.
那那个态度
Looks like...
好像
What did she say?
她跟你说啥了
She said,
说啥了
"No way. Don't even think about it."
不可能 你想都不要想
"It's impossible."
那不可能的事
That firm attitude.
那个坚决的那个样
Oh my.
天啊
I just don't understand.
真是不理解
Listen,
我跟你说啊
Lili,
丽丽
actually, it's my fault.
其实也 这事也都怪我
I always say to you
就是平时吧
how excellent
我老是跟你说
my brother's sons are.
我哥那俩儿子多优秀
I wasn't saying it
其实我真不是
for you to hear.
说给你听的
Isn't it nice
本来
to have two children,
两个孩子
one surnamed Xu
一个姓许 一个姓李
and the other Li?
不挺好吗
It's perfect.
十全十美的事
Why is she overreacting like that?
那怎么就反应那么大
Yeah, you are right.
是 我也是这么想的